In terms of autonomous control, we have a set of operators who are interested in.
Why certain actions are being taken by, in this case, this autonomous vehicle?
In some cases, the vehicle might be within sight.
In other cases, the vehicle might be out of sight, meaning that the vehicle might have access to some situation Information.
That they can't even see at that point in time.
So when they want to interrogate this, they may want to do so in a post hoc situations such as after.
After action analysis, or maybe even during the time period in which.
The vehicle.
Is up.
Performing on a mission.
So you can see, in both cases, explanations are critical to these users.
So where the x e I program is all about is to address this fundamental trade off.
For performance versus explain ability.
You may be very familiar with by now.
The uh.
Advent of deep learning and how it's impacted this trade off.
In particular, for certain types of applications, those in which.
Uh, we're working with raw sensory data.
Deep learning applications have been shown to be able to greatly increase learning performance.
But there has often been the case that it's been in the sacrifice of explain ability.
There's some notion of form.
X AI.
Is instead focused on the task of being able to increase explain ability.
Without sacrificing learning from.
Performance.
So we're trying to go to the Top right hand side of that.
Curly cues me that my graph that.
The graph that you see there.
Uh, in doing so, the goal is to be able to create a new generation.
Of AI systems that are machine learning and able.
In which users can understand uh, the uh, learned models understand why these predictions being generated.
Uh, understand when they can trust the model.
And be able to work with it effectively to manage it in upcoming.
Critical applications.
So that's a quick introduction to the x AI program.
What are we doing next?
Instead highlighting six contributions to the.
To the program.
The first three pertain to data analytics. And the latter three will be.
Pertaining to.
Autonomous control.
So the first one here pertains to a method that's called rise. This is.
Developed by the boston university sub team of uc berkeley.
So rise or um, randomize, uh.
Keep forgetting. Right? Randomized input sampling for explanations.
Is focused on the first of those questions that you were looking at before.
Why did you give me this prediction?
So here we see a surprising prediction. It's saying from this aerial imagery. And what we're looking at.
It appears to be a shopping mall. Instead predicting that a solar farm.
Which begs the question as to why?