In the last video, you learned about.
The sliding windows object detection algorithm using a constant.
But we saw that it was too slow.
In this video.
You learn how to implement that algorithm.
Constitutionally.
Let's see what this means.
Needs to build up toward the convolutional implementation of sliding windows. Let's first see how you can do.
Internet fully connected layers in your neural network.
Into convolutional layers.
We'll do that first on this slide. And then the next slide will use the ideas from this slide.
To show you the convolution.
So let's say that your object detection algorithm.
Input some 14 by 14 by three images. This is quite small, but just for illustrative purposes. And let's say.
Say it then uses um.
Fiber, five filters. And let's say uses 16 of them.
To map it from 14 by 14 by three to 10 by 10 by 16.
And then does a 2 by two max pooling to reduce it to five or five by 16.
Then um, has a fully connected layer.
To connect.
To fall into units that are not fully connected there.
And then finally outputs.
Uh, why?
Using a software.
In order to make the change, we need to in a second, I'm going to.
Change this picture a little bit. And instead I'm going to.
V y as um.
Four numbers.
Corresponding to the class probabilities of the four classes that are.
The salt tax units is closed.
Lost by a mile.
A month.
Um, and did the full classes.
Could be.
Pedestrian.
Car, motorcycle and.
Background.
Or something else.
Now what I like to do is show how these layers.
Can be turned into.
Convolutional layers.
Yes. So the confident with the drawer, same as before. For the first few layers.
And now one way of implementing this next layer is fully connected layer.
Is to implement this as a.
Five by five.
Filter.
Unless use 405 by five.
Filters.
So if you take a 5 by five by 16 image.
And convolve it with a 5 by five filter.
Remember a 5 by five filter.
Is implemented as five by five.
By 16.
Because our convention is that the filter looks across all 16 channels. So there's 16 and just 16.
Must match.
And so the output will be one by one.
And if you have.
400.
Of these five by five by 16 filters.
Then the output dimension is going to be one by one.
By 400.
And so rather than viewing these 400.
As um.
Just a set of notes. We are going to view this as a 1 by one by 400.
Volume.
And mathematically, this is the same.
As a fully connected layer.
Because each of these 400 notes.
Has.
A filter of dimension.
Five by five by 16.
And so each of those 400 values is some.
Your arbitrary linear function.
Of these five by five by 16.
Um, activation.
Friends from there previously.
Next to implement the next convolutional layer.
We're going to implement a.
One by one convolution.
And if you have.
401 by one filters.
Then.
With 400 filters. The next layer.
Will again be.
One by one.
By 400.
So that gives you this next.
Fully connected there.
And then finally.
We're going to have um.
Another one by one.
Filter.
Followed by a soft max activation.
So as to.
Give a 1 by one by full volume.
Uh, to take the place of.
These four numbers that the network was out.
So this shows how you can take these.
Fully connected layers.
And implement using.
Convolutional layers.
So that these.
A set of units instead.
Are now implemented as one by one by 400.
Hundred and one by one by.
For.
Volumes.
Armed with this conversion.
Let's see how you can.
Have a convolution.
Implementation of sliding windows object.
Object detection.
And the presentation on this slide is based on the over feet paper reference at the bottom.
By pierce, anthony, david, oregon.
Zhangjiang Michael matthew, robert fergusson, your honor.
Let's say that your.
Sliding windows, confident inputs, 14 by 14 by three in.
Teachers and.
Uh, again, I'm just using small numbers, like a 14 by 14.
In this slide.
Uh, may need to make the.
Numbers and illustration.
Which is simpler.
So as before.
You have a new network.
As follows. That eventually outputs a.
One by one by full volume.
Uh, which is the output of.
Fuel cell fax.
And begin to simplify the drawing here.
14 by 14 by three is technically a volume.
Five by five or.
10 by 10 by 16. A second. Clear volume.
But to simplify the drawing for this slide, I'm just gonna draw the front face of these volumes.
So so joy.
You know, one by one by 400 volumes.
I'm just going to order.
One by one.
Pots of all of you.
Of these rights, which is a.
Drop to.
It's really compelling.
Drawings just for this slide.
So let's say that you're confident inputs, 14 by 14 images, or 14 by 14 by three images.
And your test set images.
Which is 16 by 16 by.
So now added that yellow stripe.
To the border.
Of this image.
So in the original sliding windows algorithm.
You might.
Want to.
Uh, input the blue region.
Into a confident and run at once to generate classification 01.
And then slide it down a bit less. Use a string of two pixels.
And um.
And then you might slide.
Uh, oh, and then you might slide that to the right by two pixels.
To input this.
Green rectangle into the continent and rerun the whole continent.
And get another label, 01.
And then you might.
Input this orange region.
Into the confident.
And run it one more time to get another label.
And then do the fourth and final time.
With this the lower right?
Um.
Now.
Purple square.
And so to run sliding windows on this 16 by 16 by sea image, it's pretty small image.
You run.
This continent from above.
Four times in order to.
Get four labels.
But it turns out a lot of this computation done by these four confidence is highly duplicated.
So what the convolution and implementation of sliding windows does is it allows.
These four.
Um, for it passes into confident.
To share a lot of money.
Computation.
Specifically, here's what you can do.
You can take the confidence and just.
Run it.
Same parameters the same.
Five by five by filters are also 16.
Five by five filters.
And run it.
And now.
You can have a.
12 by 12 by 16 output volume.
And then do the max pull, same as before. Now you have a 6 by six by 16.
Run through your same.
405 by five filters to get now your.
Two by two.
By 40.
Volume.
So now, instead of a 1 by one.
So now, instead of a 1 by one, by.
400.
Volume.
You have instead a.
Two by two.
By 400.
Hundred volume.
Uh, run it through one by one filter.
Gives you another.
Two by two by 400 instead of one by one by 400.
Hundred.
Do that one more time.
And now you're left with a.
Two by two by four output volume. Is that one guy?
And it turns out that this blue one by one by four subset.
Gives you the result of running on the upper left hand.
Corner, 14 by 14 image.
This upper right?
One by one by four volume gives you.
The upper right result.
Um, the lower left.
Gives you.
The results of implementing the content on the lower left, 14 by 14 region.
And the lower right?
One by one by four volume gives you the same results as running.
The uh confident on the lower right for the breakfast.
And if you step through all the steps of the calculation, let's look at the green example.
If you had cropped out.
Just this region and pass it through the confident.
Through the confident on Top.
Than the first layer is activation.
Would have been.
Exactly this region.
The next layer is activation of the masses.
Cooling would have been exactly.
Actually, this region.
And then um.
The next layer.
Would have been as follows. So what this process does, what this confidential Information does is.
Instead of forcing you to run.
Forward propagation.
On for subset of the input image independently.
Instead, it.
Combines all four into one form of computation.
And shares a lot of computation.
In the regions of the image that are common.
To all four of the um.
14 by 14 points.
As we saw here.
Now let's go through a bigger example. Let's say you now want to run sliding windows on a 28 by 28 by three.
It turns out if you run.
For a profit. The same way.
Then you end up with an eight by eight by four output.
And this corresponds to running sliding windows with.
That 14 by 14 region.
And that corresponds to running sliding windows.
First on that.
Region.
Just giving you the output corresponding.
On the upper left hand corner.
Than using a stride or two to shift one window over.
One window over one window over.
And so on. And there a position.
So that gives you.
This first row.
And then as you.
You know goes down the image as well. That gives you all of these eight by eight by four.
Um, opens.
And and it's because of the max pooling of two.
That uh, this corresponds to running.
You're on your network with a stride of two.
On the original.
No image.
So just to recap, to implement.
Sliding windows. Previously. What you do is you.
Trump held a region.
Let's say this is um.
14 by 14.
And run that you are confident and do that for the next region over.
Then do that for the next 14 by 14 regions. And the next one, the next one, and the next one to the next one.
And so on. Until hopefully.
That one recognizes the.
The car. But now instead of doing it sequentially.
With this convolutional implementation that you saw in the previous slide.
You can implement the entire image. Or maybe 20 by 28.
And convolutional e.
Make all the predictions at the same time.
Uh, by one foot paws through this big content and hopefully have it right.
Nice the position of.
In the car.
So that's how you implement sliding windows, convolutional v, and it makes the whole thing.
Much more efficient.
Now, this album still has one weakness, which is the position of the bounding boxes.
Is not going to be too accurate.
In the next video. Let's see how you can fix that problem.